ego.co.uk 2019-11-06

# Privacy Policy | Protecting Your Privacy | EGO

## Protecting Your Privacy

At EGO, we are 100% committed to protecting the privacy and security of our customers and site visitors. The EGO team members are customers themselves, of both EGO and other internet sites – so we totally appreciate and respect how important privacy is. If you have any questions about how we Protect Your Privacy, drop us a line at **help@ego.co.uk**

For all our services, the data controller - the company that’s responsible for your privacy - is EGO Shoes Ltd

## How we use your information

We use your information in a number of different ways - what we do depends on the information. The sections below set this out in detail, showing what we do, and why we do it.

## Your name and contact details

For customers and all others who have consented for us to hold your information this is how we use your name and contact details.

Deliver your purchases to you - we’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you (it’s a bit hard to send your order if we don’t use your name and contact details!).

Send you service messages by text or email such as order updates - we’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you (so you can tell when your order is coming).

Sending you information by email, SMS, or post, about our new products and services - to keep you up to date.

Fraud prevention and detection - To prevent and detect fraud against either you or EGO Shoes Ltd- unfortunate, but absolutely essential.

Showing you EGO adverts as your browse the web - So you can see our latest products and deals.

Finding out what you, and other customers, like - To ensure we are giving you what you want, and to stay ahead of the competition.

## Your date of birth information

### How we use your date of birth

Send you information by email, SMS, or post on your birthday - to give you a birthday treat.

## Your gender information

### How we use your gender information

To direct you to the right part of our website - to get you to the products that you want faster.

## Your payment information

This means your card’s security/CVV code, don’t worry, we don’t keep these details ourselves, we use a trusted and secure payment processor.

### How we use your payment information

We use this to take payment, and give refunds - we’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you - we’re not giving all our stuff away!

Fraud prevention and detection - to prevent and detect fraud against either you or EGO Shoes Ltd - unfortunate, but absolutely essential.

## Your contact history with us

What you’ve said to us - for example, over the phone, on instant chat, or on social media.

### How we use your contact history

Provide customer service and support - we’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you, after all, you expect the best service from us.

Train our staff - so that, when you contact us, you get the best possible customer service.

## Purchase history and saved items

What you’ve bought and what you’ve stored in your basket for another time.

### How we use your purchase history and saved items

To sell you things - we’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you - if you can’t put stuff into a basket, you can’t buy it!

Provide customer service and support, and handle returns - we’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you.

Finding out what you, and other customers, like - to ensure we are giving you what you want, and to stay ahead of the competition.

To send you information and offers from time to time that you may well be interested in.

## Information about your phone or laptop, and how you use our website

Information you give us when you browse our site, including your IP address and device type and, if you choose to share it with us, your location data, as well as how you use our website and app.

### How we use information about your phone or laptop, and how you use our website

Improve our website and set default options for you (such as language and currency) - to give you the best possible shopping experience.

Protect our website - to prevent and detect fraud against either you or EGO Shoes Ltd – unfortunate, but absolutely essential - and to meet our legal obligations about looking after your data.

## Your responses to surveys, competitions and promotions

### How we use your responses to surveys, competitions and promotions

We use your responses to run the survey, competition or promotion - we’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you - if we can’t use your entry, you can’t possibly win!

You don’t have to give us any of this personal information but if you don’t, you may not be able to buy from the site, and you are unlikely to receive our optimal overall customer experience. But that is your choice - and we respect that.

We also anonymise and aggregate personal information (so that it does not identify you) and use it for purposes including testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving our site and app, and developing new products and services. We occasionally use external analytical Companies to analyse this information for us.

## Sharing your information

We do not, and will not, sell any of your personal data to any third party - including your name, address, email address or credit card information. We want to earn and maintain your trust, and we believe this is absolutely essential in order do that.

However, we share your data with the following categories of Companies as an essential part of being able to provide our services to you. These Companies are data processors who will only use your data as instructed by the data controller - EGO. When they no longer need your data to undertake the immediate tasks we have asked them to undertake, your details will be deleted by them. The statement below states how your data is shared:

Companies that do things to get your purchases to you, such as payment service providers, warehouses, order packers, and delivery Companies.

Professional service providers, such as marketing agencies, advertising partners and website hosts who help us to run our business.

Credit reference agencies, law enforcement and fraud prevention agencies, so we can help tackle fraud.

Companies approved by you where you choose to use their payment service.

We may provide data analytic Companies with aggregated but anonymised information and analytics about our customers and, before we do so, we will make sure that it does not identify you.

## Marketing messages

As a customer of EGO or someone else who has consented receive them, we may send you from time to time marketing messages by email, SMS or post, to keep you aware of what we’re up to and to help you see and find our products.

### How to stop marketing messages from EGO

You can stop receiving marketing messages from us at any time.

### You can do this:

By clicking on the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email.

By replying to the SMS and following the instructions stated.

By writing to the address listed below.

EGO   
Unit A1  
Longford Trading Estate  
Stretford  
Manchester  
M32 0JT  
UK

By contacting our Customer Care team at **help@ego.co.uk**.

Once you do this, we will update your profile to ensure that you don’t receive further marketing messages.

Please note that, as EGO comprises a complex web of many inter-connecting services, it might take a few days for all our systems to be updated, so you might get messages from us while we process your request.

Stopping marketing messages will not stop service communications such as order updates.

## Seeing adverts for EGO online

We also engage in online advertising, also to keep you aware of what we’re up to and to help you see and find our products.

Like many Companies, we target EGO banners and ads to you when you are on other websites and apps. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges, and we use a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers, as well as specific services offered by some sites and social networks, such as Facebook’s Custom Audience service.

The banners and ads you see will be based on information we hold about you, or your previous use of EGO (for example, your EGO search history, and the content you read on EGO) or on EGO banners or ads you have previously clicked on.

## Your information and countries outside Europe

We protect your privacy and your rights through the use of the European Commission’s standard data protection clauses.

## Keeping your information

We’ll hold on to your information for as long as you have your account, or as long as is needed to be able to provide the services to you, or (in the case of any contact you may have with our Customer Care team) for as long as is necessary to provide support-related marketing and trend analysis only – this will be no longer than 2 years after your last purchased date.

If required to meet legal or regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our terms and conditions, we may also keep hold of some of your information as required, even after you have closed your account or it is no longer needed to provide the services to you.

## Your rights

You have a lot of rights relating to your personal information:

The right to be informed about how your personal information is being used

The right to access the personal information we hold about you

The right to request the correction of inaccurate personal information we hold about you (although you can probably do most of this through My Account

The right to request that we delete your data, or stop processing it or collecting it, in some circumstances

The right to stop direct marketing messages and to withdraw consent for other consent-based processing at any time

The right to request that we transfer or port elements of your data either to you or another service provider

The right to complain to your data protection regulator - in the UK, the Information Commissioner’s Office

If you want to exercise your rights, have a complaint, or just have questions, please contact us at **help@ego.co.uk** or pop your request **[here](https://ego.co.uk/gdpr-form/)**.

## Changes to how we protect your privacy

We may change this page from time to time, to reflect how we are processing your data.

If we make significant changes, we will make that clear on the EGO website or by some other means of contact such as email, so that you are able to review the changes before you continue to use EGO.

## Cookies

### What about cookies?

We use cookies when you visit our site. There are four main types of cookies – here’s how and why we use them.

1\. Site functionality cookies - these cookies allow you to navigate the site and use our features, such as “Add to Bag” and “Save for Later”.

2\. Site analytics cookies - these cookies allow us to measure and analyse how our customers use the site, to improve both its functionality and your shopping experience.

3\. Customer preference cookies - when you are browsing or shopping on EGO, these cookies will remember your preferences (like your language or location), so we can make your shopping experience as seamless as possible, and more personal to you.

4\. Targeting or advertising cookies - these cookies are used to deliver ads relevant to you. They also limit the number of times that you see an ad and help us measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

By using our site, you agree to us placing these sorts of cookies on your device and accessing them when you visit the site in the future. If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, the “help” section in your browser should provide instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. Further information about cookies can be found **[here](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-pecr/cookies-and-similar-technologies/)** . Please note that by deleting or disabling future cookies, your user experience may be affected and you might not be able to take advantage of certain functions of our site, and the complete EGO user experience that we pride ourselves on providing our customers.”

## How to contact us

We always want to hear from our customers (especially if you feel we’ve let you down or could do better).

### If you:

Have any questions or feedback about this notice

Would like us to stop using your information

Want to exercise any of your rights as set out above, or have a complaint

Please don’t hesitate to contact our Customer Care team, who will be happy to answer any questions you may have.

You can contact our privacy team by dropping us a line at **help@ego.co.uk**. Or if you’d like to, you can write to us at:

EGO   
Unit A1  
Longford Trading Estate  
Stretford  
Manchester  
M32 0JT  
UK
